# Hawk Weisman

## February 16, 2016

I'M A COMPUTER SCIENTIST, engineer, and researcher. I love solving interesting and challenging problems, learning new things, and making neat stuff. My primary interests are programming languages, systems programming and operating systems, and tools for software engineering.

hi@hawkweisman.me 990 First Street, Meadville, PA 16335 (814) 853-1501

### Skills

I have a lot of experience with functional programming techniques in a number of languages, and a focus on writing high-quality, idiomatic code. I'm also familiar with modern software development techniques, practices, and tools, and I've worked in a number of areas, such as web development, programming languages, and systems programming. Some of my favourite tools include:

LANGUAGES Fluent in Scala, Rust, Python, and Java; familiar with Haskell, Clojure, C, and R

LIBRARIES Frameworks: Scalatra, Bootstrap, Polymer; testing: ScalaTest, ScalaCheck, QuickCheck, JUnit, Mock-

ito; other: Akka, Slick

TOOLCHAIN Build systems: Gradle, SBT, Ant, Cargo, Make; editors and IDEs: Atom, SublimeText, IntelliJ IDEA;

collaboration: GitHub, GitLab, Jenkins, Travis

#### Education

I'M PURSUING A BACHELOR OF SCIENCE in Applied Computing with a focus in Software Engineering. My coursework has included:

Data Structures and Algorithms Computer Organization
Principles of Software Engineering Operating Systems

Principles of Data Management Introduction to Compiler Design
Programming Language Implementation Robotics and Multi-Agent Systems

B.S. IN APPLIED COMPUTING Allegheny College, Meadville, PA Expected May 2016 GPA: 3.67

### Experience

Wrote a simple operating system kernel for x86\_64, primarily in Rust, to learn more about OS design and development. Implemented a bootloader in x86 assembly, and interrupt handling, memory allocation, VGA console and PS/2 keyboard drivers, and other operating system features in Rust.

Fall 2015 — Ongoing Personal Project https://github.com/hawkw/ sos-kernel

COFOUNDED A SMALL BUSINESS to develop and publish independently developed computer games, and designed and implemented a game engine in Scala, contributing over 9,000 lines of Scala source code to the project.

SPRING 2014 — ONGOING MeteorCode Laboratories https://github.com/meteorcode/ pathway

Designed and implemented Mnemosyne, a new functional language intended for systems programming, implementing a compiler in Rust using LLVM, and wrote a language specification.

Fall 2015 — Ongoing Senior Thesis Allegheny College https://github.com/hawkw/mnemosyne

Designed and implemented Seax, a virtual machine-based runtime for programs in functional languages. Wrote the VM and a compiler for Scheme programs in Rust.

Spring 2015 Independent Study Allegheny College https://hawkweisman.me/seax